Guide to the Herman Axelbank Motion Picture Film Collection 1896-1977
Hoover Institution Archives
- Shreider and other Provisional Government leaders; Shreider at an election rally during his campaign for mayor of Petrograd (147-169) government leaders, army veterans, conservative group, priests in conservative faction; Miliukov (169-181) Trotsky speaking from the steps of a train, May 17(181-195) Kerensky (195-207) Plekhanov arriving, speaking from platform (207-243) Kornilov; parade of officer cadets; cossacks (243-270) Kerensky on balcony; arriving at a meeting with a bouquet (270-281) National Socialist group (identified as such by text frame) (281-290) U.S. Senator Elihu Root (290-308) Kronstadt Central Executive Committee, June 1917(308-324) Albert Thomas, French Socialist minister, in Petrograd; Henderson, British socialist, in Petrograd; Tereshchenko, Minister of Foreign Affairs (324-346) Bolshevik demonstration--Kollontai speaks; Kronstadt sailor speaks; leaflets distributed (346-368), May-June 1917; Segment 2; 04:40:33 (Reel 18)
  147 (4/449)
  Miliukov, Pavel Nikolaevich; Shreider, Grigorii Il'ich; Kornilov, Lavr Georgievich; Trotskii, Lev; Thomas, Albert; Tereshchenko, Mikhail Ivanovich; Kollontai, Aleksandra Mikhailovna; Kerenskii, Aleksandr Fedorovich; Plekhanov, Georgii Valentinovich; Root, Elihu; Henderson, Arthur
  Rossiiskaia sotsial-demokraticheskaia rabochaia partiia; Elections; Mayors; Provisional Government
  Sound: 181-207; 243-281; 324-346
- Poster for Liberty Loan; patriotic demonstration (0-13) Kerensky at the front, tossed in the air by soldiers (13-18) Women's Battalion marching, drilling, rifle practice; group picture; British officer, Florence Harper and Emmeline Pankhurst; Pankhurst greets Bochkareva, Commander of Women's Battalion; Bochkareva and Pankhurst review Woman's Battalion (18-46) Elections to City Duma--crowds; leaflets being dropped from cars; truck with a "Peace, Land, Bread" banner; orator; crowds; leaflets (46-65) Women's Battalion in Moscow--induction ceremony on Red Square; oath of loyalty (65-75) pro-Kerensky demonstration, parade; banner: "Forward with our Leader Kerensky" (75-80) opening of First All-Russian Congress of Soviets in Petrograd, June 16--crowds; delegates arriving in car (80-106) infantry attacking (106-116), June-July 1917; Segment 1; 04:40:41 04:43 (Reel 19)
  0 (4/504)
  Harper, Florence MacLeod; Pankhurst, Emmeline (Goulden); Bochkareva, Mariia L.; Kerenskii, Aleksandr Fedorovich Demonstrations--Provisional Government period; World War, 1914-1918--Campaigns--Galician front; World War, 1914-1918--Patriotic response to; Women's Battalion; Military ceremonies--Provisional Government period; Duma, City (Petrograd); Elections; Vserossiiskii sezd sovetov, lst, Leningrad, June-July 1917; Processions--Provisional Government period
  Sound: 0-18; 46-81; 106-116
- July Days--demonstrations; banners, July 1, 1917(116-148) Vynnychenko, Ukrainian separatist leader (148-152) soldiers' demonstration (soundtrack says Bolshevik sympathizers attack officers whose banners have imperialist slogans; Axelbank's description says rightists attack Bolshevik banner carriers) (152-165) pro-government demonstration by troops of the Petrograd garrison (165-202) crowd in front of Novoe vremia newspaper office (202-208) Kronstadt sailors on truck with Bolshevik slogans; crowds; demonstrations; marching (208-229) soldiers firing on demonstrators (229-240) photo of Lenin at grave of fallen communists, with Angelica Balabanoff, Felix Kuhn (later Polish delegate to the Comintern), Christian Rakovsky, and others (240-246) Ksheshinskaia Palace--interior in ruins following raid by cossacks and garrison troops (246-257), July 1917; Segment 2; 04:47:84 (Reel 19)
  116 (4/531)
  Lenin, Vladimir Il'ich; Balabanoff, Angelica; Kuhn, Felix; Rakovskii, Khristian Georgievich; Vynnychenko, Volodymyr Kyrylovych
  Rossiiskaia sotsial-demokraticheskaia rabochaia partiia; Demonstrations--Provisional Government period
  A; B. 229-240(?)
  Sound: 116-139; 152-165; 229-240
- Area near Sestroretsk where Lenin was in hiding following July Days; Lenin's false passport; photo of Lenin as Ivanov in Finland (257-278) Petrograd--anti-Bolshevik orators, cossack officer addressing the crowd (278-300) men leaving through factory gates; crowds in front of a store, mostly women (300-313) soldier smoking; soldiers with leaflets; wounded soldiers getting off trains; soldiers boarding trains; soldiers with leaflets; workers stoking a fire; orator in a factory (313-333) orator in the countryside speaking to peasants; soldier speaking (333-345) Kornilov and cavalry (345-349) Boris Savinkov (349-354) opera house in Moscow where State Conference was held, August 25(354-358) pro-Bolshevik demonstration, Red Square, August 1917(358-369), August 1917; Segment 3; 04:50: (Reel 19)
  257 (4/563)
  Lenin, Vladimir Il'ich; Savinkov, Boris Viktorovich; Kornilov, Lavr Georgievich
  Moscow State Conference, August 1917; Demonstrations--Provisional Government period; Soldiers, Revolutionary; Rossiiskaia [UNK] rabochaia partiia
  Leningrad; Moscow; Sestroretsk; Finland
  A; B. orator in factory?
  Sound: 295-300; 328-369
- Moscow State Conference--crowds outside opera house; delegates arrive at opera house; Kerensky arrives; Kornilov arrives; David Francis, American Ambassador; French, British and other Allied diplomats; Buchanan, British Ambassador, and his daughter arrive in cab; Miliukov, Guchkov, Tereshchenko, Shul'gin; Rodzianko, Karaulov, Kaledin (0-52), August 1917; Segment 1 (Reel 20)
  0 (4/588)
  Buchanan, Meriel; Buchanan, George William, Sir; Miliukov, Pavel Nikolaevich; Guchkov, Aleksandr Ivanovich; Tereshchenko, Mikhail Ivanovich; Shul'gin, Vasilii Vital'evich; Karaulov, Mikhail Aleksandrovich; Kaledin, Aleksei Maksimovich; Rodzianko, Mikhail Vladimirovich; Francis, David Rowland
  Moscow State Conference, August 1917
  Moscow
  Sound: 0-9; 16-37; 50-52
- German attack on Riga--soldiers; views of the city; Germans shelling the city; Germans ride into Riga (52-68) Kornilov's march on Petrograd--tanks; armored cars; armed citizens; armored cars; street scenes in Petrograd; crowds in front of Ksheshinskaia Palace; Sverdlov entering Palace; crowds; orators (68-126), September 1917; Segment 2; 04:52 04:54:34 (Reel 20)
  52 (4/600)
  Sverdlov, IAkov Mikhailovich; Kornilov, Lavr Georgievich World War, 1914-1918--Campaigns--German front
  Riga; Leningrad
  Sound: 52-80; 90-121
- Posters being put up for elections to the Constituent Assembly (126-143) Bolshevik orator (143-145) rifles being distributed (145-148) Trotsky speaking (148-151) house in Petrograd where Lenin hid (151-156) armed workers; garrison troops who came over to the Bolsheviks with armored cars (156-170) soldiers leaving the front on foot, in trains (170-179) crowds on the street in front of a bank (179-189) Winter Palace Square--soldiers; civilians; log barricades erected by junkers (caption text) (189-239), September-November 1917; Segment 3; 04:54:35 (Reel 20)
  126 (4/615)
  Trotskii, Lev
  Soldiers, Revolutionary; Elections; Constituent Assembly
  Political posters
  Sound: 156-179
- October Revolution--soldiers armed with rifles; cannons (239-249) Kerensky (said to be last film of Kerensky prior to his flight) (249-253) Smolny Institute, fortified, guarded; armored car inscribed "Lieutenant Schmidt" (253-268) Kronstadt sailor guarding a door; armed sailors; Battleship Aurora; armed workers; sailors; Smolny; armed workers marching; storming of the Winter Palace (268-350) Winter Palace as it looked the day following the Bolshevik seizure of power (350-359), November 6, 7, 1917; Segment 4; 04:57 05:01:03 (Reel 20)
  239 (4/638)
  Kerenskii, Aleksandr Fedorovich
  October Revolution (November 1917 N.S.)
  A; B. 268-350
  Sound: 239-268; 275-350
- October Revolution (cont.)--photograph of Red Guards on trucks; RSFSR on red flag over Winter Palace (0-9) Post and Telegraph Building; Ministry of Interior Building; Justice Ministry Building; Telegraph Exchange; destroyed officers' club (9-29) Morse code transmitter (29-32) soldiers at the front fraternizing (32-55) Nikolai Krylenko; Dybenko, leader of Kronstadt sailors (55-59) Lenin at Petrograd Soviet, November 7, 1917;page from Lenin's first manifesto (59-75) red flag over Smolny; Lenin's desk, room, chair at Smolny; pages from documents; newspaper pages showing Lenin's decrees (75-101), November 1917; Segment 1; 05:03:04:14 (Reel 21)
  0 (5/016)
  Krylenko, Nikolai Vasil'evich; Dybenko, Pavel Efimovich; Lenin, Vladimir Il'ich
  October Revolution (November 1917 N.S.); Russian Soviet Federated Socialist Republic
  A; B. 59-75
  Sound: 0-9; 29-59
- October Revolution in Moscow--government forces with cannon from arsenal of Kremlin used to fight off Bolshevik insurgents; cannon firing from Kremlin; Kremlin following capture by Red Guards (101-120) peasant man, woman, horse plowing (120-123) Mikhail Kalinin, President of RSFSR, receiving written petitions from ordinary citizens (123-133), November 1917; Segment 2; 05:05:55: 05:06:48: (Reel 21)
  101 (5/070)
  Kalinin, Mikhail Ivanovich
  Sound: 110-113; 120-133
- Brest-Litovsk Peace Conference--Kamenev, Ioffe, Karakhan, Radek, Bitsenko arriving on train; Radek; Bitsenko and Karakhan; Ukrainian delegation; Piatakov; Russian delegation on the way to conference hall; German delegation; photo of the two delegations facing each other across the conference table (133-175) Trotsky arrives at Brest-Litovsk (175-186), Dec. 1917-March 1918; Segment 3; 05:06:48 (Reel 21)
  133 (5/086)
  Ioffe, Adol'f Abramovich; Kamenev, Lev Borisovich; Radek, Karl; Bitsenko, Anastasiia Alekseevna; Piatakov, Georgii Leonidovich; Trotskii, Lev; Karakhan, Lev Mikhailovich
  Brest-Litovsk Peace Conference, 1917-1918
  Brest-Litovsk
  Sound: 133-150; 175-186
- Anti-war demonstrations in Germany; corpses of demonstrators (186-199) Hindenburg and Ludenforff (199-204) German offensive into Ukraine following Brest-Litovsk--German soldiers attacking; cavalry; infantry; shells exploding; soldiers on a boat; Lufendorff talking; Russian POWs; captured war materiel; bridges destroyed by the Bolsheviks; Germans pushing supply wagons in the mud; German soldiers in the snow; on parade in a village; soldiers eating; Germans marching into Kiev (204-293), March 1918; Segment 4; 05:11:15 (Reel 21)
  186 (5/111)
  Ludendorff, Erich; Hindenburg, Paul von, Pres. Germany
  Demonstrations--Germany; World War, 1914-1918--Campaigns--Ukraine
  Kiev; Ukraine; Germany
  Sound: 186-293
- Chaikovskii, SR, leader of anti-Bolshevik government at Archangel; British ships supplying Chaikovskii; Chaikovskii and David R. Francis, American Ambassador; American barracks and soldiers; soldiers erecting a building; American supply sleds; Americans and residents of Archangel bartering using sign language; outpost in the Far North--residents; American flag over Red Cross building; Russian children; American soldiers (293-376), 1918; Segment 5; 05:11:16:01 05:13:33:07 (Reel 21)
  293 (5/156)
  Chaikovskii, Nikolai Vasil'evich; Francis, David Rowland Severnaia oblast'; Civil War, 1918-1921--American intervention; Civil War, 1918-1921--British intervention; Soldiers, American
  Civil War, 1918-1921--Campaigns--Northwestern front
  Archangel
  Sound: 294-306
- Bolshevik prisoners captured by British and Americans--shown in a group; sawing wood; their barracks; prisoners working around barracks (0-38) Japanese battleship Hizzon (which had been a Russian battleship before it was captured by the Japanese during the Russo-Japanese War) in Vladivostok Harbor; officers of the Hizzon; soldiers in winter clothes and fur hoods marching (38-60) President Wilson (60-64) American officers getting out of car, posing for camera (64-77) railroad yard, train arriving; officers examining the contents of a boxcar (77-87) Allied forces marching in a snowy city square (87-92) U.S. battleship South Dakota in Vladivostok Harbor (92-105) soldiers of the various interventionist powers coming down a flight of stairs; posing in a group for the camera (105-129) ships in the harbor; flags; British marines disembarking; forming ranks; marching on dock; marching down a street; British marine guarding British consulate (129-172), 1918; Segment 1; 05:13:41:12 (Reel 22)
  0 (5/191)
  Wilson, Woodrow, Pres. U.S.
  Civil War, 1918-1921--American intervention; Civil War, 1918-1921--British intervention; Civil War, 1918-1921--Campaigns--Northwestern front; Prisoners of war; Civil
  War, 1918-1921--Prisons and prisoners; Severnaia oblast'; Civil
  War, 1918-1921--Allied intervention; Civil War, 1918-1921--Japanese intervention; South Dakota (Battleship); Hizzon (Battleship); Civil War, 1918-1921--Campaigns--Far East
  Archangel; Vladivostok
  Sound: 38-43; 105-129
- Headquarters of the Czech Legion--American officer, White officers, officers of various interventionist powers salute, go inside, come back outside, form into a group facing the camera (172-215) Czech Legion military and civic headquarters--leader (in sheepskin hat) greets civilian and military figures (215-259) man and woman (aware of camera) walk up to store window, strike up conversation in front of store window (Omsk?), then walk away together (woman identified by one historian as Kolchak's mistress) (259-294) Chinese soldiers at Khabarcvsk--first aid tent; camels; fording a river (294-307) Chekists with confiscated grain; ships at a dock; Chekists in cars in front of a house (caption: a house search) (307-345), 1918; Segment 2; 05:18:35 5:21:28 (Reel 22)
  172 (5/254)
  Civil War, 1918-1921--Allied intervention; Civil War, 1918-1921--American intervention; Czech Legion; Civil War, 1918-1921--Campaigns--Siberia; Civil War, 1918-1921--Campaigns--Far East; Civil War, 1918-1921--Chinese intervention; Cheka
  Omsk; Khabarovsk; Siberia
- Funeral of assassinated Chekist (0-12) firewood being stacked outside to be used to heat government offices (12-21) May Day, 1918, Petrograd; huge canvas revolutionary-theme posters in Winter Palace Square (21-36) May Day parade in Petrograd (36-49) Lenin in Moscow; Krupskaia and Lenin's sister Mariia in car with Lenin (49-60), 1918; Segment 1; 05:23:29 5:23:30 (Reel 23)
  0 (5/312)
  Lenin, Vladimir Il'ich; Ul'ianova, Mariia Il'inichna; Krupskaia, Nadezhda Konstantinovna
  Cheka; Funeral Service--Cheka agent; May Day (Labor holiday), 1918; Political posters
- May Day(?) parade (60-71) mounted officer reviewing troops; Denikin (71-78) Trotsky speaks to soldiers (78-85) former tsarist officers now in Red Army--Vatsetsis, first commander-in-chief; Brusilov; Trotsky with Kamenev, tsarist general who became commander-in-chief after Vatsetis; Kamenev; Voroshilov, Kamenev, Borodin(?) (85-94) Red Army officers leave Trotsky's headquarters in the Kremlin (94-98) Volodarsky, Commissar of Press and Propoganda, who was assassinated by an SR June 21, 1918(98-101) views of Kremlin (101-110) 1916 film of tsar and his family (same as reel 14, segment 1); photo of house where they were executed; photo of death chamber; (?)Axelbank says the group photo is of the Tsar's slayers, but the soundtrack says that some of them were arrested, some executed (110-121) Lenin and Krupskaia leaving after Lenin had given a speech to a workers' union audience (121-122) Uritsky's funeral--Zinoviev present; Dzerzhinsky (122-137) Civil War; Kazan campaign--group of soldiers with rifles and flag pose for camera; Trotsky arrives at the Kazan Front by train; Trotsky stands next to a soldier who is looking for documents in his own pockets; Trotsky reviews troops after Kazan taken (137-159), Summer 1918; Segment 2; 05:25.10:15 05.27.55 (Reel 23)
  60 (5/330)
  Lenin, Vladimir Il'ich; Krupskaia, Nadezhda Konstantinovna; Uritskii, Moisei Solomonovich; Kamenev, Sergei Sergeevich; Denikin, Anton Ivanovich; Gol'dshtein, Moisei Markovich; Trotskii, Lev; Voroshilov, Kliment Efrimovich; Brusilov, Aleksei
  Alekseevich; Vacietis, Jukums; Zinov'ev, Grigorii; Dzerzhinskii, Feliks Edmundovich; Borodin, General; Nicholas II, Emperor; Alexandra, Empress Consort of Nicholas II, Emperor; Ol'ga
  Nikolaevna, Grand Duchess; Tat'iana Nikolaevna, Grand Duchess; Mariia Nikolaevna, Grand Duchess; Anastasiia Nikolaevna, Grand Duchess; Aleksei Nikolaevich, Tsarevich
  May Day (Labor holiday), 1918; Military ceremonies--Soviet period; Funeral service--Uritskii, Moisei Solomonovich; Civil War, 1918-1921--Campaigns--Kazan
  Kazan; Moscow; Sverdlovsk
  Sound: 78-94; 101-159
- Lenin standing by a car, walking, talking with Bonch-Bruevich in Kremlin (159-264) illus. of Lenin from book (264-267) Lenin speaking at unveiling of statue of Marx and Engels in Moscow, Nov. 7, 1918(266-289) Lenin and Sverdlov inspecting Red Air Force, 1919(film of airplanes, photo of Lenin) (289-297), Oct.-Nov. 1918, 1919; Segment 3; 05:27:55 5:30:50 (Reel 23)
  159 (5/359)
  Lenin, Vladimir Il'ich; Bonch-Bruevich, Vladimir Dmitrievich; Sverdlov, IAkov Mikhailovich
  October Revolution (November 1917 N.S.)--Anniversary, 1918; Air Force, Soviet
  Sound: 215-223; 264-266; 289-297
- Prominent Bolsheviks, in a group, including Bukharin, Krylenko, Sokol'nikov, Piatakov; leading Bolsheviks shown individually--Kamenev; Sosnovskii; Rakovskii; unidentified figures; Red Army officer; unidentified persons; Lunacharskii; two persons seated, civilian reading document to person in military uniform; Rumiantsev; unidentified; Krasin (last person shown) (297-358), 1918; Segment 4; 05:31:47 05:33:28 (Reel 23)
  297 (5/398)
  Bukharin, Nikolai Ivanovich; Krylenko, Nikolai Vasil'evich; Sokol'nikov, Grigorii IAkovlevich; Kamenev, Lev Borisovich; Sosnovskii, Lev Semenovich; Rakovskii, Khristian Georgievich; Lunacharskii, Anatolii Vasil'evich; Rumiantsev, Petr Petrovich; Krasin, Leonid Borisovich; Piatakov, Georgii Leonidovich
  Sound: 297-314
- Comnunist uprising in Germany--crowds in the streets; military figures; Karl Liebknecht; military figures; corpse of Liebknecht (0-34) scenes from Proskurov in the Ukraine--corpses of victims of Petliura's forces; people mourning victims (34-55), 1919; Segment 1; 05:33:38 05:35:10 (Reel 24)
  0 (5/416)
  Liebknecht, Karl Paul August Friedrich; Petliura, Symon Vasyl'ovych
  German Revolution, 1918; Civil War, 1918-1921--Campaigns--Ukraine; Jews in the Ukraine--Persecution
  Germany; Ukraine; Proskurov
  Sound: 0-34
- Photo of Lenin; First Congress of the Comintern, Kremlin--Lenin flanked by Eberlein, German delegate (left); Platten (right); Klinger, Eberlein, Lenin, Platten (55-73) Andreichin, Bulgarian delegate (73-76) delegates (76-81) Lenin speaks at funeral of Mark Elizarov, first People's Commissar of Railways, husband of Lenin's sister Anna; funeral procession; Lenin, his grief visible, in crowd (81-131), March 2,10, 1919; Segment 2; 05:35:10 05:37:17:17 (Reel 24)
  55 (5/431)
  Lenin, Vladimir Il'ich; Eberlein, Hugo; Platten, Fritz; Andreichin, Georgi Iliev; Geyer, Curt; Elizarov, Mark Timofeevich
  Communist International. 1st Congress, Moscow, 1919; Funeral
  service--Elizarov, Mark Timofeevich
- German soldiers in the Baltic Region--mounted column travelling on a snowy road (131-133) Zinov'ev gives speech standing on a truck (133-136) funeral of Sverdlov, March 18, 1919--funeral procession; Zinov'ev speaks; Lenin speaks; Lenin in crowd of mourners (136-198) scenes of Hungarian Communist uprising--soldiers; Bela Kun (198-220), 1919; Segment 3; 05:37:17 05:39:47 (Reel 24)
  131 (5/450)
  Zinov'ev, Grigorii; Lenin, Vladimir Il'ich; Sverdlov, IAkov Mikhailovich; Kun, Bela
  Civil War, 1918-1921--Campaigns--Northwestern front; Funeral service--Sverdlov, IAkov Mikhailovich; Hungarian Revolution, 1918-1919
  Hungary
  Sound: When Lenin is speaking at Sverlov's funeral, soundtrack is describing a speech he would have given in 1917.
- Red Square--Lenin giving a speech; review of troops; parade (220-251) Lenin in car, during visit to Rublevskoi Water Power Station outside Moscow (251-257) Makhno(?) (257) officers in car (258-262) Vladivostok Harbor--on American Battleship South Dakota, William Sidney Graves, Commander of the American Expeditionary Force, receives Czech War Cross from General Cecek, Czech Legion Commander; Dr. Girsa, Czech diplomatic representative in Siberia, also present (262-278) Lenin and Krupskaia leaving a session of the First Congress on Extracurricular Education; Lenin stops to talk (278-303) Miliukov and Kerensky, in Paris seeking French assistance against the Bolsheviks; Clemenceau (303-319) Admiral Kolchak inspects a wood-burning gunboat on the Irtish River; reviews troops, including cossacks (319-352), May 1, 1919; Segment 4; 05:39:48:03 05:43:32:09 (Reel 24)
  220 (5/473)
  Lenin, Vladimir Il'ich; Makhno, Nestor Ivanovich; Graves, William Sidney; Cecek, General; Krupskaia, Nadezhda Konstantinovna; Girsa, Dr.; Kolchak, Aleksandr Vasil'evich; Kerenskii, Aleksandr
  Fedorovich; Miliukov, Pavel Nikolaevich; Clemenceau, Georges Eugene Benjamin
  May Day (Labor holiday), 1919; Civil War, 1918-1921--American intervention; Civil War, 1918-1921--Campaigns--Far East; Civil War, 1918-1921--Campaigns--Siberia; Czech Legion; South Dakota (Battleship)
  Vladivostok; Moscow; Paris; Omsk; France; Siberia
  Sound: 272-278; 303-352
- Kolchak accepting bread, salt, and live geese from local leaders; priest leading procession of residents of Omsk to church to pray for Kolchak's victory (0-22) Lloyd George, Orlando, Clemeneau, Wilson; diplomats at Peace Conference leaving and entering sessions; Lloyd George, Briand and others (22-43) train passing by a town in flames; sunflowers; field with haystacks burning (43-53), 1919; Segment 1 (Reel 25)
  0
  Kolchak, Aleksandr Vasil'evich; Wilson, Woodrow, Pres. U.S.; Orlando, Vittorio Emanuele; Briand, Aristide; Lloyd George, David, Lloyd George, 1st Earl; Clemenceau, Georges Eugene Benjamin
  Civil War, 1918-1921--Campaigns--Siberia; Orthodox Eastern Church, Russian; Paris. Peace Conference, 1919; Civil War, 1918-1921
  Omsk; France; Siberia
  Sound: 0-31
- Vladivostok, celebration of 75th anniversary of YMCA--a gymnasium with flags of the various interventionist forces decorating the walls; Vladivostok children practice American-style physical training, military-style marching and drills; group of children with American woman; Red Cross representatives; girls practicing drills; children and American woman; gymnastics; games; dancing on stage; seesaws; dancing; drilling; Czech gymnasts; American soldiers boxing; Japanese combat in ring with wooden weapons (53-217) Kolchak's gunboat at Tobolsk; Kolchak with his troops at Tobolsk (217-233), 1919; Segment 2 (Reel 25)
  53
  Kolchak, Aleksandr Vasil'evich
  Civil War, 1918-1921--Campaigns--Siberai; Civil War, 1918-1921--American intervention; Civil War, 1918-1921--Japanese intervention; Civil War, 1918-1921--Allied intervention; Gymnasts; Czech Legion; Young Men's Christian Associations; Red Cross
  Vladivostok; Tobolsk; Siberia
  Sound: 217-233
- Lenin, with Red Army commanders, reviews new contingent of Red Army recruits on completion of their training; Lenin, in a group, enters Red Square; Lenin, Krupskaia, Mariia Ul'ianova, Szamuely (Hungarian Communist leader); Red Army recruits; Lenin talks to recruits; Lenins reviews troops, Budenny on his left; Lenin, on truck, shakes hands with man in crowd (233-312), May 25, 1919; Segment 3; 05:50:16 (Reel 25)
  233 (5/561)
  Lenin, Vladimir Il'ich; Szamuely, Tibor; Budennyi, Semen Mikhailovich; Ul'ianova, Mariia Il'inichna; Krupskaia, Nadezhda Konstantinovna
  Military ceremonies--Soviet period